buildium.com 2019-05-31

# Privacy Policy | Buildium

Last updated August 13, 2018

## How We Protect You

Buildium, LLC (“Buildium”) is committed to protecting the privacy of information and data that may be used to identify you, your personal information. The intention of this privacy policy (the “Privacy Policy”) is to disclose our information-gathering practices and describe how we use your personal information. The effective date of this Privacy Policy is August 13, 2018.

## Information We Collect

We collect personal information from you if you use our website, fill out forms on our website or on paper at events, or use any of our web-based products or services. The types of personal information we collect include, but are not limited to, the following:

  * Contact details, such as name, title, company name, email address, phone number, and mailing address
  * Taxpayer ID numbers (including social security numbers in the case of sole proprietors)
  * Credit card information processed by our payment processor (Buildium does not retain your full credit card information)
  * Personalization information including, but not limited to, an uploaded profile photo
  * Details about your interest in our products and services
  * Responses to surveys, polls, or assessments
  * Information collected automatically from our website visitors including, but not limited to, your IP address, web browser, language, operating system, the date and time you accessed our website, and the link from which you accessed our website

## How We Use Your Personal Information

The personal information that we collect is used to perform our contractual obligations and for our other legitimate interests. In some cases, we may ask you for your consent to use your personal information, but any consent will be presented to you separately from this Privacy Policy. We may use your personal information for purposes including, but not limited to, the following:

  * To deliver services, products, or transactions that you have requested
  * To improve our website, including upgrading security measures
  * To send you promotional materials or communications regarding our content and services that we feel may be of interest to you
  * To evaluate the products and services that we offer and develop new or improved products or services and to better understand Buildium’s business environment
  * For educational purposes, such as polls conducted in webinars
  * To conduct general research on topics of interests to Buildium and its customers

## How We Share Your Personal Information

We may share your information for any of these purposes with the following individuals and entities:

  * Vendors engaged by Buildium to provide certain services to you, including, but not limited to, payment processing management, credit screening, and vacancy management. Buildium maintains contracts with our vendors requiring them to only use your personal information as necessary to provide their services and requiring them to comply with the requirements of this Privacy Policy and applicable laws.
  * Services used by Buildium to aid our ability to provide the best possible experience to you.
  * Buildium may need to share your information for law enforcement or other legal purposes. This type of sharing may be necessary in connection with a lawsuit, claim or investigation, governmental inquiry, court order, enforcement of legal rights (e.g., contract terms, intellectual property rights, etc.), safety issue, or other similar legal or security matter. Sharing your information for these reasons is not a regular event, but could arise from time to time. We will strive to limit the types and amount of information we may need to share for legal purposes to that which is reasonably necessary.
  * We may share (or receive) information about you, including personal contact information, in the event of an acquisition, merger, sale, corporate restructuring, bankruptcy, or other similar event that involves Buildium. If such an event occurs, Buildium will take reasonable steps to require that your information be handled in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

Buildium will never sell, rent, or disclose your personal information to third-party entities except as described in this Privacy Policy.

## Transfer of Information to the United States

Buildium is headquartered in the United States. Information we collect from you will be processed in the United States. The United States has not sought nor received a finding of “adequacy” from the European Union. With respect to transfer from the European Union, Buildium relies on derogations for specific situations. In particular, Buildium collects and transfers personal information to the United States only with your consent, to perform on a contract with you (or in your interest), or to fulfill a compelling legitimate interests of Buildium in a manner that does not outweigh your rights and freedoms. Buildium endeavors to apply suitable safeguards to protect the privacy and security of your personal information and to use it in a manner that is consistent with this Privacy Policy. Buildium does not collect sensitive data such as data concerning health, gender, racial or ethnic origins, or genetic or biometric (known as special categories of data in the European Union) or personal information from children.

## Data Retention

Buildium retains personal information for as long as we have a legitimate business relationship with you or with an organization with which you are affiliated (such as your employer). We may also retain personal information about prospective customers or prospective employees until we determine that it is unlikely that we will provide you with services and/or employ you. We also may retain your personal information for as long as necessary to comply with our legal or contractual obligations.

## Your Rights

If you do not want to receive promotional or marketing communications from Buildium, you may opt-out at any time by clicking the “unsubscribe” link at the end of our emails. If you choose to unsubscribe, we will retain your contact information to ensure that we do not contact you again.  
If you are located in the European Union, you may have the following legal rights under European Union law:

  * To withdraw consent at any time, if we are processing your personal information on the basis of consent
  * To access the personal information Buildium has about you
  * To request that Buildium rectify or erase your personal information
  * To request that Buildium restrict the way it uses your personal information
  * To object to the way Buildium uses your personal information
  * To ask Buildium to transfer your personal information to someone else
  * To lodge a complaint with a data protection agency in the European Union

EU residents that would like to request that their data be securely removed from our systems please follow these steps outlined in our [Data Removal Process](https://www.buildium.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/Buildium-Data-Removal-Process.pdf). If you are unable to remove the data please send a request to [privacy@buildium.com](mailto:privacy@buildium.com) and Buildium will remove all relevant data, so long as that removal is technically feasible, does not impact the accounting or business practices of our customers, and does not violate other regulatory or legal standards with which Buildium must comply.

## Data Protection Addendum

Follow this link to the [Data Protection Addendum](https://rightsignature.com/forms/DPA8-28-203655/token/c919c8517a8) which includes all required terms for GDPR compliance, plus Standard Contractual Clauses which serve as a safeguard to govern transfers of personal data out of the EU/EEA/Switzerland.

## Security

Buildium uses a number of security technologies and procedures to ensure your personal information is protected from unauthorized access, use, or disclosure. However, we cannot guarantee that third parties will not overcome these measures and gain access to your information. To the fullest extent permitted by law, Buildium disclaims any warranty or guarantee that your information will be protected from misuse, appropriation, alteration, or loss.

## Links to External Websites

This website contains links to websites that are not controlled by Buildium. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the content, security, and privacy practices of external sites. We encourage you to familiarize yourself with the privacy policy of all websites where you submit personal information.

## Cookies We Use

We and our authorized partners may use cookies and other information gathering technologies for a variety of purposes. These technologies may provide us with personal information, information about devices and networks you utilize to access our Websites, and other information regarding your interactions with our Websites. For detailed information about the use of cookies on the Websites, please read and review our [Cookie Policy](https://buildium.com/privacy-policy/cookie-policy).

## Changes to Privacy Policy

From time to time, Buildium may change or update this Privacy Policy. We recommend you regularly review this page. When we update this Privacy Policy, we will also revise the “last updated” date at the top of this page. Buildium will use reasonable commercial efforts to notify you of changes to this Privacy Policy that materially change the disclosures made here.

## For California Residents

**California “Do Not Track” Notice.** Buildium does not currently recognize and process “do not track” signals from different web browsers. For more information on “do not track” please visit [http://www.allaboutdnt.org](http://www.allaboutdnt.org/).

**California Privacy Rights.** Pursuant to Section 1798.83 of the California Civil Code, residents of California have the right to request from a business, with whom the California resident has an established business relationship, certain information with respect to the types of personal information the business shares with third parties for direct marketing purposes by such a third party and the identities of the third parties with whom the business has shared such information during the immediately preceding calendar year. If you are a California resident and want a copy of this notice, please submit an email request to privacy@buildium.com. In your request, please specify that you want a “Your Buildium California Privacy Rights Notice.” Please allow 30 days for a response.

## Contact Information

If you have questions about how we handle your personal data, please contact us by phone or email.

Phone number: 1-888-414-1988  
Email: [privacy@buildium.com](mailto:privacy@buildium.com).
